



Bimalesh Sahoo

Nationality: Indian

**** (+49) 15739689677

Date of birth: 25/08/1995

Gender: Male

Email address: sahoo.bimalesh@gmail.com

Website: https://sahoobimalesh.in

Skype: bimalesh.sahoo

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bimaleshsahoo

Address: Kupferstraße 7A 310, 85049 Ingolstadt (Germany)

ABOUT ME

Pursuing M.Sc. in User Experience Design at Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt. A Developer converted to a Creative Designer with around 4 years of professional experience working in the field of User Experience Design. Original and clever with the ability to work with design and development teams. Better understanding of requirements, business goals, branding document guidelines and converting prepared solutions into innovative wireframes by creating work flows and interactive prototyping designs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Experience Designer

Dassault Systèmes [31/10/2019 – 26/11/2020]

Address: Pune (India) - https://www.3ds.com/

City: Pune Country: India

- Involved in define and design of Document Management Application on the 3DEXPERIENCE Platform.
- Completed user research to identify opportunities for improving web presence.
- Facilitated clients' product vision by researching, conceiving, sketching, prototyping.
- Designed UI elements and components such as navigation menus, search boxes, tabs and widgets for digital components.

User Experience Designer

Wipro Limited [25/07/2016 – 11/10/2019]

Address: Pune (India) - https://www.wipro.com/en-IN/

- Designed and built advanced applications for the iPhone, iPads, Web platform.
- Collaboration with functional teams to define, design and ship new features.
- Have got a great exposure with clients and customers by working with them.
- Worked in a fast paced, agile and in an ownership and results oriented culture.
- Close interaction with the development teams to get the best out of designs.
- Ability to handle and lead a team ensuring deliverables within stipulated time.



EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Science

Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt [01/11/2020 – Current]

Address: Ingolstadt (Germany)

https://www.thi.de/

Field(s) of study: User Experience Design

Bachelor of Engineering

Sikkim Manipal Institute of Technology [16/07/2012 - 15/07/2016]

Address: Gangtok (India) https://smu.edu.in/smit.html

Field(s) of study: Electronics and Communication Engineering.

National classification: Grade - 9.1 (GPA)

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office / Adobe Creative Cloud / Figma / UX UI Design / Product Designer / Mobile Design / Axure Rp 9 / Interaction Design / Design Thinking

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Odia

Other language(s):

English German

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1